ASHUTOSH SRIVASTAVA

+91-9035158152

ashutosh.srivastava93@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-srivastava1/



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

EDUCATION

B. Tech (Information Technology) from UPTU with 70%

TECHNICAL SPECIALIZATIONS

- Manual, Automation Testing
- SQL
- Selenium Web Driver
- Test automation framework development using C# & Java

TESTING TOOLS

- Eclipse
- Selenium
- Postman
- Visual Studio
- Azure Dev Ops
- SpecFlow

TEST MANAGEMENT TOOLS

- JIRA, Confluence
- HP ALM
- Mantis

DOMAIN

- ERP
- Banking (BFSI) applications (MFGI, MFGA)
- Oracle forms applications
- Web based applications

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATIONS

- ISTQB CFL Testing certification.
- Awarded with the Above & Beyond and Super Team for outstanding performance in DMS.Nxt project.
- Awarded with the Super Team for JPMC - MULTIFONDS project.

GITHUB

https://github.com/ashutoshx/JIRA-API-automation-framework

BACKGROUND

Working as an Automation Test Engineer with one of the Big4, having total 6 years of work experience in Banking & Finance domain. With a quick turnaround time, worked on various Banking products and Automation Tools as per business requirement. Highly organized and independent, able to effectively coordinate the tasks to accomplish the Projects with timeliness.

Experience in developing Cucumber BDD Test Automation Framework and executing Test Scripts as per the requirements, participating in Reviews, Defect Tracking and Reporting and preparing status report.

WORK HISTORY

KPMG Global Services (JAN 2021 - PRESENT)

CONSULTANT

- Managing the whole Automation Test cycle for an application related to managing the accounts for multiple clients.
- Automation test script creation and execution using Selenium with C# on Visual Studio.
 - Managing Code review, merge, push & pull using Azure Dev ops.

TEMENOS (DEC 2018 - DEC 2020)

TEST ENGINEER

- Creation of Test cases using Eclipse Design Studio (EDS)
 Automation tool. Working on Fund Accounting product MFGA and testing the full E2E functional requirements related to FRD's.
- Worked on interface files for loading static data, transactions, orders, prices. Creating static data setups in testing environment using SQL queries. Planning and estimations of the activities in regression releases.
 - Analysing Test Execution results.

KPMG (APR 2015 - DEC 2018)

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT

- Performed Regression, Functional, E2E testing & UAT of the application.
 - Develop test cases and prioritize testing activities.
- Ensure that all tested related work is carried out as per the defined standards and procedures. Track the defects till closure.
 - Interact with client for customization & clarification.
 - Follow up with client for scenarios review & signoff.
 - Participate in defect triage to prioritize the defects.
 - Work with Dev. & environment teams for application issues.
 - Prepare scenarios, test data, test cases for Regression, UAT.



EXPERIENCE

- Engineering Professional with 6 years of Manual and Automation Software testing experience.
- Experience in test framework creation using Selenium with C# and Java using Visual Studio & Eclipse.
- Experience in using **SQL** gueries to create static data setups for the application.
- Experience of developing Cucumber BDD (Behaviour Driven Development) Test Automation Framework.
- Experience in understanding the Customer Requirements and deriving Test Scenarios based on the Requirement.
- Experience in JIRA, Confluence, Azure Dev Ops, Mantis, HP ALM and SQL developer tools.
- Integrate the framework into **Jenkin** CI/CD tool and Azure Dev Ops.
- Developing end to end functionality with all validation & assertions.
- Well versed with the concept of Serialization & Deserialization to dynamically build the JSON payload for framework.

PROJECTS

PROJECT 1: Fund Management System

Client Name: Qatar National Bank Business Domain: Fund Accounting

Location: Doha, Qatar

Project description: Testing the system that manages the Fund Management for the Qatar National Bank. Testing of Investment Bank Fund Management system dealing with Equities, Derivatives, Mutual Funds, Corporate Actions.

Role & responsibilities:

- Performed Regression, Functional, E2E testing & UAT of the application.
- Managed the full testing process of Integra application (Mutual Funds), Corporate actions.
- Client interaction for customization & clarification.
- Develop test cases and prioritize testing activities.
- Ensure that all tested related work is carried out as per the defined standards and procedures.

PROJECT 2: Multifonds Global Investor Application (MFGI)

Client Name: JP Morgan Chase & Co Business Domain: Transfer Agency

Location: Bangalore, India

Project description: Multifonds Global Investor is a transfer agency and investor servicing system that supports global assets. It consolidates investor servicing and transfer agency operations onto a single, industrial-scale platform across all investment fund types.

Role & responsibilities:

- Track the defects till closure.
- Performing E2E & functional testing.
- Interact with client for customization & clarification.
- Follow up with client for scenarios review & signoff.
- Track the status of scenario & test cases preparation.
- Work with development & environment teams for application issues.
- Prepare scenarios, test data, test cases for Regression, UAT.

PROJECT 3: DMS.Nxt

Client Name: Samsung India Electronics Limited (SIEL)

Business Domain: ERP **Location:** Gurgaon, India

Project description: DMS.Nxt is an upgraded version of the current Distribution Management System (DMS) used by the Samsung India Electronics Limited (SIEL) for different divisions.

Role & responsibilities:

Preparation and Execution of test cases based on functional document received.



- Analyzing the requirement from FRD and BRD.
- Involved in designing, executing and reviewing test cases and logging the defect in JIRA.
- Involved in peer review with the team members.
- Work with developers in fixing the defects that are blockers for testing
- Prepare scenarios, test data, test cases for Regression, UAT.